Guide to the Oskar Morgenstern Papers, 1866-1992 and undated RL.10033
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Mathematica Materials, 1958-1977, 3 boxes
  - Memoranda, 1970-1977, 2 folders (Box 91)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1961, undated, 2 folders (Box 91)
  - Introduce Mathematica, 1963-1971 (Box 91)
  - Lockheed Consulting, 1963-1970 (Box 91)
  - Marketing, 1967-1971 (Box 91)
  - Marketing - Government, 1964-1969 (Box 91)
  - MARSEP, 1965-1969 (Box 91)
  - Mathematica, 1964-1966, 1969, 1975, 1977, undated, 2 folders (Box 91)
  - NASA, 1970 Sep.-Dec. (Box 91)
  - NASA, 1972 (Box 92)
  - NASA - Space Expenditure and the National Economy, 1971 (Box 92)
  - Negotiation Models, 1975 (Box 92)
  - Navy Supply System Research, 1960 Jun. (Box 92)
  - Notes, 1959 (Box 92)
  - Office of Naval Research, 1973-1974, undated (Box 92)
  - Office of Naval Research Conference, 1974 (Box 92)
  - Office of Naval Research Workshop on Economic Conflict and National Security Research, 1976 (Box 92)
  - Office of Naval Research - Research and Development, 1964-1968 (Box 93)
  - Operations Research Society of America of The Institute of Management Sciences Joint National Meeting, 1975 (Box 93)
  - Oskar Morgenstern Distinguished Fellowship, 1977 (Box 93)
  - Plowshare (Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Explosions), 1967.-1971 Mar., undated, 4 folders (Box 93)
  - Plowshare - Correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 93)
  - Plowshare: Experiment in a New Form of Industry, 1967-1969 (Box 93)
  - Plowshare - Notes, Reports, Miscellaneous Documents, 1966-1967 (Box 93)
  - Plowshare - Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 93)
  - Plowshare - Research and Technology, 1967, 1969 (Box 93)
  - Plowshare - Support Files, 4 folders (Box 93)
  - Plowshare - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, Sandia, 1965, 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 93)
  - Portable Energy Conference, 1974 (Box 93)
  - Projecting the Power of National and Regional Systems, 1969 Apr. (Box 93)
  - Physica-Verlag, 1970-1975 (Box 93)
  - Readings in Research Management, 1964 Nov. (Box 93)
  - Research Management Project, 1964-1965 (Box 93)
  - Sandia Corporation, 1958-1976, 4 folders (Box 93)
  - Statement to the Senate Aeronautical and Space Sciences Committee, 1972 (Box 93)
  - Statistical Revenue Accounting for Airlines - Tibor Fabian, undated (Box 93)
  - Slonim, Gilven M., 1970-1972 (Box 93)
  - Temper, 1965-1967 (Box 93)
  - Transportation in Japan, 1969 (Box 93)
  - University Relations, 1967, 1971 (Box 93)
  - U.S. Strategic Options for the 1970s - Comment on Rathjens Paper, 1968 Nov. (Box 93)
  - Weekly Activity Report, 1962 (Box 93)
- Printed Material Series, 1929-1976
  Pamphlets, articles, and a few books relating to economic theory and problems written by persons other than Morgenstern. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1929-1971, 8 folders (Box 66)
  - 1973-1976 and undated, 6 folders (Box 67)
- Audiovisual Series, 1957-1977 and undated
  Films and audiotape featuring Morgenstern and a school, the Wirtschaftshochschule Mannheim.
  - J. von Neumann, Dec. 2, 1954, 1954 December 2; 1 items (Box 122, Audio-reel RL10033-RR-0001)
    - Original 1/4-inch open-reel audiotape (Box 122, Audio-reel RL10033-RR-0001)
  - Talk at Scudder, Stevens & Clark, New York City, December 31, 1962, 1962 December 31; 1 items
    - Original 1/4-inch open-reel audiotape (Box 122, Audio-reel RL10033-RR-0002)
  - The Campus Library, Economics Series, Economic Theory, by Dr. Oskar Morgenstern, Professor of Economics at Princeton University, copyright 1964, 1 items
    - Original 1/4-inch open-reel audiotape (Box 122, Audio-reel RL10033-RR-0003)
  - 50-Jahrfeier der Wirtschaftshochschule Mannheim. Fackelzug der Studenten (Feier in Schlosshof). Zug der Professoren und der auswrtigen Hochschulvertreten zum Musensaal des Rosengartens. 1957, Dec. 9-11. 10 minutes. 1 reel. Film. (Box 68)
  - Dem Zufall Eine Chance Geben. Ein Portrt des Nationalkonomen Oskar Morgenstern. Ein Film von Theo Pirker und Christian Grote. Gemeinschaftsproduktion des Bayerischen Rundfunks-Studienprogramm. 1972. 58 minutes 50 seconds. Typescript also. 3 reels. Film. (Box 68)
  - T.C. Merkle Memorial Lecture, Lawrence Radiation Laboratory, Livermore, California, March 21, 1968. 1 reel. Audio tape. (Box 68)
  - Discussion of Morgenstern's The Question of National Defense (1959) on Today Television Show. Film. 10 minutes. (Box 69)
  - Le Futur Sans Erreur. Interview by Marc Gilbert of the Office de Radiodiffusion-Television Franaise broadcast on the program Un Certain Regard. 1974. 50 minutes. 2 reels. Film. (Box 69)
- Accessions (1999-0265) and (1999-0438)
  - Information Series, 1934-1976 and undated
    - Distinguished Fellow of the AEA, 1976. (Box 70)
    - Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1976. (Box 70)
    - "Das Grosse Golden Ehrenzeichen, 1970,1976. (Box 70)
    - Honorary Doctorate, 1965. (Box 70)
    - Honorary Life Member of the New York Academy of Sciences, 1976. (Box 70)
    - Universitas Basiliensis 1460-1960, 1960 (in storage tube) (Box 71)
    - Die Wirtschaftshochschule Mannheim, 1957 (in storage tube) (Box 72)
    - Paul D. Converse Award, 1967. (Box 73)
    - Universitas Basiliensis 1460-1960, 1960. (Box 73)
    - Photo Album, undated (Box 73)
    - Photographs undated, 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Autobiographical Material (Box 74)
    - Bibliographical Material (Box 74)
    - Biographical Material (Box 74)
    - Lucie Morgenstern, undated (Box 74)
    - Willy Morgenstern, undated (Box 74)
    - Bilder aus Muldenthal" by Willy Morgenstern, undated (Box 74)
    - Familie Morgenstern" by Willy Morgenstern, 1934., 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Der Morgenstern, 1940-1950, 2 folders (Box 74)
    - The family Teichler, undated (Box 74)
  - Correspondence Series, 1925-1992
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restricted. See Usage Restrictions and consult Research Services staff for further information.
    - Briefe von Oskar, 1940-1950, 3 folders (Box 74)
    - 1925 Dec.-1926 Feb. (Box 74)
    - 1930 Oct.-1939 May (Box 74)
    - 1940 July-1949 March (Box 74)
    - 1951 Feb.-1958 Oct. (Box 74)
    - 1960 Jan.-1969 April (Box 74)
    - 1970 June-1979 Jan. (Box 74)
    - 1980 Dec.-1988 Nov. (Box 74)
    - 1990 Feb.-1992 March (Box 74)
    - Luigi Einaudi, Feb. 1928 - Aug. 1961. (Box 74)
  - Writings and Speeches Series, 1931-1977 and undated
    - Diary, 1939. (Box 75)
    - Appointment books, 1948-1977, 5 folders (Box 75)
    - Chronological: 1931 July-1967 April (Box 75)
    - Chronological: 1967 July-1974 Feb. (Box 75)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 75)
    - Abraham Wald, 1902-1950, 1951. (Box 75)
    - Die Anwendung der Spieltheorie in der Wirtschaftswissenschaft, 1968. (Box 75)
    - L'attitude de la Nature et le Comportement Rationnel, undated (Box 75)
    - Las ciencias sociales en el umbral de nuevas evluciones, 1966. (Box 75)
    - Civil Defense: Economic Problems, 1966. (Box 75)
    - The Collaboration Between Oskar Morgenstern and John von Neumann on the Theory of Games, 1976. (Box 75)
    - The Command and Control Structure, 1962. (Box 75)
    - Competition and Collusion in Bilateral Markets, 1976. (Box 75)
    - Complementarity and Substitution in the Theory of Games, 1950. (Box 75)
    - The Compressibility of Economic Systems and the Problem of Economic Constants, 1966. (Box 75)
    - Computation of Economic Programs, 1950. (Box 75)
    - Consistency Problems in the Military Supply System, 1955. (Box 75)
    - Consumo privado y pblico y ahorro en el modelo Von Neumann de una economa en expansin, 1970. (Box 75)
    - Descriptive, Predictive and Normative Theory, 1972. (Box 75)
    - Econometric Computations in the Large, 1954. (Box 75)
    - L'conomie est elle une science?, 1971. (Box 75)
    - rtkelmletek, 1930. (Box 75)
    - L'Etude des conjectures en Autriche, 1935. (Box 75)
    - The Experience with Public Regulation and Public Monopoly Abroad, 1938. (Box 75)
    - Experiment und Berechnung grossen Umfangs in der Wirtschaftswissenschaft, 1956 (Box 75)
    - Fragen der Verteilungslehre mit besonderer Berchsichtigung der Theorie der Grenzproduktivitt, 1925. (Box 75)
    - Further Consideration of 'An Open Expanding Economy Model,' 1971. (Box 75)
    - Game Theory, 1948-1973. (Box 75)
    - Game Theory and the Phenomenon of Power, 1975. (Box 75)
    - General Discussion on Past and Future of the Von Neumann Model, 1974. (Box 75)
    - A Generalization of the Von Neumann Model of the Expanding Economy, 1956. (Box 75)
    - "A Graph Oriented Model for Research Management, 1966. (Box 76)
    - I Tre Tipt Fondamentali Della Teoria Del Valore Soggettivo, 1934. (Box 76)
    - Input-Output Relations, 1953-1955. (Box 76)
    - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1968. (Box 76)
    - La Introdzione e la Abolizione del Controllo dei Cambi Esteri in Austria (1931-1934), 1937. (Box 76)
    - Ist der Weltfriede Unvermeidlich?, 1967. (Box 76)
    - Kapital - und Kurswertnderungen der an der Wiener Brse notierten sterreichischen Aktiengesellschaften 1913 bis 1930, 1932. (Box 76)
    - Limiti e condizioni dei programmi economici, 1951. (Box 76)
    - Limite al Empleo de las Matemticas en las Ciencia Econmica, 1965. (Box 76)
    - The Limits of Economics, 1937. (Box 76)
    - Limits to the Uses of Mathematics in Economics, 1963. (Box 76)
    - Logistica e scienze sociali, 1951. (Box 76)
    - Logistik und Sozialwissenschaften, 1936. (Box 76)
    - Long Term Planning with Models of Static and Dynamic Open Expanding Economies, 1974. (Box 76)
    - Die Macht im Handel der Staaten: Ein Problem der Theorie des internationalen Handels, 1936. (Box 76)
    - Mathematical Economics, undated (Box 76)
    - Mathematical Theory of Expanding and Contracting Economies, errata for, 1976. (Box 76)
    - Methoden und Grezen der Konjunkturpolitik, 1956. (Box 76)
    - Un modle de croissance en conomie ouverte, 1971. (Box 76)
    - National Defense, 1958-1961. (Box 76)
    - Nature's Attitude and Rational Behavior, 1966. (Box 76)
    - The N-Country Problem, 1961. (Box 76)
    - A New Look at Economic Time Series Analysis, 1961. (Box 76)
    - New Uses for the New Knowledge, 1968. (Box 76)
    - Note on the Formulation of the Theory of Logistics, 1955. (Box 76)
    - A Note on An Open Expanding Economy Model, 1972. (Box 76)
    - Note of the Role of Follow-ups in the Naval Supply System, 1952. (Box 76)
    - Notes on a Theory of Organization, 1951. (Box 76)
    - Nuove considerazioni sulla teoria della domanda, 1952. (Box 76)
    - Offene Probleme der Kosten - und Ertragstheorie, 1931. (Box 76)
    - konometrische Berechnungen in Grossen, 1952. (Box 76)
    - On the Accuracy of Economic Observations, undated (Box 76)
    - On the Application of Game Theory to Economics, 1962. (Box 76)
    - On the Growth and Decay of Knowledge, 1964. (Box 76)
    - On the International Spread of Business Cycles, 1943. (Box 76)
    - On Some Criticisms of Game Theory, 1964. (Box 76)
    - An Open Expanding Economy Model, 1969. (Box 76)
    - Pareto Optimum and Economic Organization, 1964. (Box 76)
    - Perfect Foresight and Economic Equilibrium, undated (Box 76)
    - Political Conjecture in Military Planning, 1968. (Box 76)
    - Prolegomena to a Theory of Organization, 1951., 2 folders (Box 76)
    - The Random-Walk Hypothesis of Stock Market Behavior, 1964. (Box 76)
    - Report on the Conference on Game Theory, 1971. (Box 76)
    - Some Critical Thoughts on Military Research and Development, 1965. (Box 76)
    - Some Reflections on Utility, 1975. (Box 76)
    - Some Thoughts on Maxims of Behavior in a Dynamic Environment, 1976. (Box 76)
    - Spieltheorie: Ein neues Paradigm der Sozialwissenschaft, 1968. (Box 76)
    - State Department, 1960. (Box 76)
    - Studi di metodologia economica, 1955. (Box 76)
    - A Study of Linear Economic Systems, 1957. (Box 76)
    - Sull'accuratezza delle statistiche del reddito nazionale e del progresso economico, 1963. (Box 76)
    - "Symmetric Solutions of Some General n-Person Games, 1961. (Box 77)
    - La teoria dei giochi e del comportamento economico, 1951. (Box 77)
    - Die Theorie der Spiele und des wirtschaftlichen Verhaltens, 1950. (Box 77)
    - Theory of Games and Economic Behavior (Box 77)
    - Thirteen Critical Points in Contemporary Economic Theory: An Interpretation, 1972. (Box 77)
    - Trece puntos crticos de la teora econmica contempornea: una interpretacin, 1974. (Box 77)
    - Treize points critiques de la thorie conomique contemporaine. Une interprtation, 1974. (Box 77)
    - ber die Genauigkeit wirtschaftlicher Beobachtungen, 1952. (Box 77)
    - Unemployment: Analysis of Factors, 1941. (Box 77)
    - La valeur du programme spatial des Etats-Unis: tude conomique, 1969. (Box 77)
    - The Validity of International Gold Movement Statistics, 1955. (Box 77)
    - Vollkommene Voraussicht und Wirtschaftisches Gleichgewicht, undated (Box 77)
    - When is a Problem of Economic Policy Solvable?" 1953. (Box 77)
    - Wirtschaftsprognose, 1928. (Box 77)
    - The Worth of the Space Program: Economics, 1967. (Box 77)
    - Das Zeritmont in der Wertlehre, 1934. (Box 77)
    - Zeitschrift fr Nationalkonomie, 1929-1932. (Box 77)
  - Subject Files Series, 1949-1982 and undated
    - Afriat, S. N., 1961. (Box 77)
    - Arrow, K., 1966-1969. (Box 77)
    - Berger, G. and A. Cournand, 1969-1974. (Box 77)
    - Borch, K., 1963-1967. (Box 77)
    - Brams, S., 1977. (Box 77)
    - Die Brcke", 1949. (Box 77)
    - Congressmen, Senators, Members of Cabinet, and other Government officials, 1970 -1976. (Box 77)
    - De Finetti, B., 1975-1977. (Box 77)
    - Econometric Research Program, undated (Box 77)
    - Essays in Mathematical Economics in Honor of Oskar Morgenstern, 1967-1969. (Box 77)
    - Game Theory, 1963-1971. (Box 77)
    - Granger, C., 1961-1967. (Box 77)
    - Harsanyi, J., 1962-1969. (Box 77)
    - Institut de France, 1967-1969. (Box 77)
    - International Journal of Game Theory, 1971. (Box 77)
    - Kissinger, H., 1969-1974. (Box 77)
    - Lecture Notes for Econ 314 at Princeton Univ., 1942-1965. (Box 77)
    - Measurement Error, 1965. (Box 77)
    - Merck-Knoppers, 1972-1976. (Box 77)
    - Mommsen-Krup, 1973-1975. (Box 78)
    - NYU, 1970-1974. (Box 78)
    - NYU and Hourmouzis Georgiadis, 1970-1972. (Box 78)
    - Plott, C., 1971-1974. (Box 78)
    - Princeton Univ., 1952-1968. (Box 78)
    - Schotter, A., 1977. (Box 78)
    - The Scottish Book, 1957. (Box 78)
    - Shubik, M., 1976-1977, 3 folders (Box 78)
    - Silk, L., 1973-1982. (Box 78)
    - Silverberg, G., 1972. (Box 78)
    - Thompson, G., 1960-1976. (Box 78)
    - Univ. of Chicago, 1965. (Box 78)
    - Von Neumann, J., 1945-1972. (Box 78)
    - Weil, R., 1964-1967. (Box 78)
    - Wirtschaftshochschule Mannheim, 1957. (Box 78)
    - Zentralvereinigund der Architekten sterreichs, 1967. (Box 78)
  - Printed Material Series, 1953-1986
    - 1953-1986, 5 folders (Box 78)
    - 1953-1986, 4 folders (Box 79)
  - Audiovisual Materials Series, 1968-1974 and undated
    - Oskar Morgenstern speech at Livermore Laboratory, March 21, 1968. Audio tape., 1 reel (Box 79)
    - On Kurt Gdel [includes info on Oskar Morgenstern and an interview with Dorothy Morgenstern], undated VHS videocassette. (Box 79)
    - Porsche notes, May 1974. Audio cassette. (Box 79)
  - Oversize Materials, 2 folders
    - Illustrations for Theory of Games and Economic Behavior (Oversize-folder 1)
- Accession (2006-0067), 22 boxes, 1 ovsz. folder
  Addition (06-067) (2452 items, 13.5 lin. ft.; dated 1935-1976) contains primarily published works by Morgenstern and his major co-authors such as John von Neumann and Gerald L. Thompson in English, French, Spanish, Italian, and German arranged in alphabetical order. Important works contained in this series include typed manuscript portions of Theory of Games and Economic Behavior with annotations, draft chapters of the Question of National Defense, Long Term Planning with Models of Static and Dynamic Open Expanding Economies, the Mathematica Economic Analysis of the Space Shuttle System and some correspondence, as well as supporting documentation and statistics. There are also three audiotape reels with Morgenstern's lectures.
  This accession is available for research, but has not been processed. A basic boxlist is included below. Items have been sorted into 2 subseries: Writings by Morgenstern and Writings by Others. Audiotapes and volumes are housed in Box 121 and 122.
  - Writings by Morgenstern (Box 102)
    - Abraham Wald, 1902-1950, 1951 (Box 102)
    - Accuracy Foreign Trade Section, undated (Box 102)
    - Accuracy New Material, undated (Box 102)
    - Aggregation and Errors in Input-Output Models by O. Morgenstern and T.M. Whitin, 1953 (Box 102)
    - Allegmeines Statistisches Archiv, 1930 (Box 102)
    - Allyn Abbott Young, 1929 (Box 102)
    - American Statistician: Fide Sed Ante Vide- Remarks to Mr. R.T. Bowman's Comments, 1964 (Box 102)
    - Annali Di Statistica E Di Economia, 1936 (Box 102)
    - Article on the Cold War, undated (Box 102)
    - Bemerkungen uber die Problematik der Amerikanischen Institutionalisten, undated (Box 102)
    - Bergedorfer Gesprache zu Fragen der freien industriellen Gesellschaft, 1966 (Box 102)
    - Besprechungen, 1952 (Box 102)
    - Book Reviews, etc., 1950-1960 (Box 102)
    - Book Review: a Graph Oriented Model for Research Management by O. Morgenstern, R.W. Shepard and H. Grabowski, 1972 (Box 102)
    - Book: Francis Y. Edgeworth, 1927 (Box 102)
    - Brochure for Institut Fur Hohere Studien Und Wissen Schaftliche Forschung, 1965 (Box 102)
    - Bulletin Sedeis, 1963 (Box 102)
    - Chap X: a Graph Oriented Model for Research Management by O. Morgenstern, R.W. Shepard and H. Grabowski, undated (Box 102)
    - Chapter 7: on the Accuracy of Economic Observations: Foreign Trade Statistics, undated (Box 102)
    - Chapter 9, Including Non-stat. Experiments (Box 102)
    - Chapter XII (Formerly Part of Old Chapters XI and XII): the Gold Supply and its Distribution,undated (Box 102)
    - Chapter XII: the Gold Supply and its Distribution, undated (Box 102)
    - Che puo la logistica per le scienze sociali?, 1951 (Box 102)
    - Command and Control Structure, 1962 (Box 102)
    - Communication with Specific Industries on Accuracy, undated (Box 102)
    - Competition and Collusion in Bilateral Markets by O. Morgenstern and Gerhard Schwodiaver, 1976 (Box 102)
    - Complementarity and Substitution in the Theory of Games (Summary) by Oskar Morgenstern, 1950 (Box 102)
    - Complementarity and Substitution in the Theory of Games- Summary, 1950 (Box 102)
    - Compressibility of Economic Systems and the Problem of Economic Constants, 1965 (Box 102)
    - Compressibility of Economic Systems and the Problem of Economic Constants, 1966 (Box 103)
    - Compressibility of Economic Systems and the Problem of Economic Constants, 1965 (Box 103)
    - Compressibility of Economic Systems and the Problem of Economic Constants, 1966 (Box 103)
    - Compressibility of Organization and Economic Systems, 1954 (Box 103)
    - Computation of Economic Progrms (Reprint),1950 (Box 103)
    - Consistency Problems in the Military Supply System (Reprint from Naval Research Logistics Quarterly vol.1, No.4, 1954 (Box 103)
    - Consistency Problems in the Military Supply System, 1954 (Box 103)
    - Consumo privado y publico y ahorro en el modelo Von Neumann de una economia en expansion, by O. Morgenstern and L. Thompson, 1970 (Box 103)
    - Contribution to the Interpretation of the Von Neumann Expanding Economy Model - Notes, 1966 (Box 103)
    - Das Zeitmoment in der Wertlehre, 1934 (Box 103)
    - Data Sheets: Price, Consumption and Production of Gold (Box 103)
    - Demand Theory Reconsidered, 1948 (Box 103)
    - Demand Theory Reconsidered, undated (Box 103)
    - Der Stand und die nachste Zukunft der Konjunkturforschung, 1933 (Box 103)
    - Der theoretische Unterbau der Wirtschaftspolitik, 1956 (Box 103)
    - Die Anwendung Der Spietheorie in Der Wirtschaftswissenschaft, 1968 (Box 103)
    - Die Einordnung der Verkehrspolitik in die Allegmaire Wirtschaftspolitik, 1936 (Box 103)
    - Die Industrie: Das Wissen Wachst Uns Uber Den Kopf, 1965 (Box 103)
    - Die Macht im Handel der Staaten, 1963 (Box 103)
    - Die Theorie der Spiele und des wirtschaftlichen Verhaltens, undated (Box 103)
    - Die Wirtschaftlichen Folgen Technischer Veranderungen (Box 103)
    - Does GNP Measure Growth and Welfare?,1975 (Box 103)
    - Does GNP Measure Growth and Welfare?,1975 (Box 103)
    - Dup, undated (Box 103)
    - Dup, undated (Box 103)
    - Dup, undated (Box 103)
    - Econometric Computations in the Large, 1954 (Box 104)
    - Economics (from Astronautics and Aeronautics), 1968 (Box 104)
    - Economics of The Space Shuttle, 1972 (Box 104)
    - Economie Appliquee,1974 (Box 104)
    - Effective Secure Deterrence: the Ocean System (from Royal Canadian Air Forcr Staff College Jounral), 1960 (Box 104)
    - Einzelschriften der Deutschen Statistischen Gesellschaft, 1952 (Box 104)
    - El Trimestre Economico, vol.XLI, No.151, 1974 (Box 104)
    - Employment Statistics, undated (Box 104)
    - Employment: Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 104)
    - Entstehung und Abbau der osterreichischen Devisenbewirtschaftung, 1935 (Box 104)
    - Ertekelmeletek, 1930 (Box 104)
    - Executive, 1960 (Box 104)
    - Executive, 1964 (Box 104)
    - Experience with Public Regulation and Public Monopoly Abroad,1938 (Box 104)
    - Experience with Public Regulation and Public Monopoly Abroad,1939 (Box 104)
    - Experiment on Complex Demodulation (III): Sample Comparision between A and B, undated (Box 104)
    - Experiment on Complex Demodulation B1-B5, undated (Box 104)
    - Experiment on Complex Demodulation D1-D5, undated (Box 105)
    - Experiment on Complex Demodulation E1-E5, undated (Box 105)
    - Experiments on Complex Demodulation, undated (Box 105)
    - Extra Sheets of "Analysis of National Defense", undated (Box 105)
    - Fide Sed Ante Vide: Remarks to Mr. R.T. Bowman's "Comments" (from American Statistician Vol.18, No.4) 1964 (Box 105)
    - For Accuracy, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 105)
    - Foreign Service Journal: Decision Theory and the Department, 1960 (Box 105)
    - Foreign Trade (Box 105)
    - Foreign Trade 1, Notes and Talks Worksheet, Manuscript, undated (Box 105)
    - Forumulation of a National Security Policy, 1976 (Box 105)
    - Four Reviews of Benjamin Ward: What's wrong with Economics?, 1972 (Box 105)
    - Further Consideration of "An Open Expanding Economy Model" by Oskar Morgenstern and Gerald L. Thompson, 1971 (Box 105)
    - Game Theory (?) drafts, undated (Box 106)
    - Game Theory (?) drafts, undated (Box 106)
    - Game Theory (?) drafts, undated (Box 106)
    - Game Theory (?) drafts, undated (Box 106)
    - Game Theory (?) papers (draft), undated (Box 106)
    - Game Theory, undated (Box 106)
    - Game Theory: Theoretical Asppects from International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1968 (Box 106)
    - Games - 314-408, undated (Box 106)
    - Games - Addenda, undated (Box 106)
    - Games (p.409-520), undated (Box 106)
    - Games (p.521-680), undated (Box 106)
    - Games Chapter 4: Zero Sum 3-Person Games, undated (Box 106)
    - Games Chapters 7-8, 1942, undated (Box 106)
    - Games Current Notes, Manuscript, undated (Box 106)
    - Games: Chapter 6: General Theory of Zero sum n-Person Games, undated (Box 106)
    - General Report on the Economics of the Peaceful Uses of Underground Nuclear Explosions by O. Morgenstern and Klaus-Peter Heiss, undated (Box 107)
    - Goal: an Armed, Inspected, Open World (from Fortune), 1960 (Box 107)
    - Gold and Foreign Security Markets - Typed Tables - Chapter 12, undated (Box 107)
    - Gold Circulation,undated (Box 107)
    - Gold Movements, 1945 (Box 107)
    - Gold Points,undated (Box 107)
    - Gold Stock, Circulation and Reserves, 1945 (Box 107)
    - Gold, 1958-1959 (Box 107)